<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- COPYRIGHT 2002 PolyGlot, Inc. -->
<!DOCTYPE doc [
<!--Netscape 6.2 has external entity bug; must manually include instead) --><!ENTITY projects SYSTEM "rbwResumeGuts.xml">
]>
<!--
See http://www.dpawson.co.uk/xsl/sect4/N9068.html
for mini-tutorial on multi-browser compatability with XSLT
-->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="Resume-MS-TR-WD.xsl" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="Resume-MS-XSL.xsl" alternate="no"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="Resume-NS-XSL.xsl"?>
<resumes>
  <person name="Robert Bruce Wallace, Jr.">
    <phone>770-995-1993</phone>
    <fax>770-237-5712</fax>
    <website>http://www.polyglotinc.com/</website>
    <address state="GA" city="Lawrenceville" zip="30043" street="331 Ashbourne Trail"/>
    <email>rbw@polyglotinc.com</email>
    <!--&projects; (Netscape 6.2 has external entity bug; must manually include instead) -->
    <project start="3/2003" end="3/2003">
      <position title="Author" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="OnJava.com" location="Sebastopol, CA" www="http://www.onjava.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="chromatic" title="Editor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Wrote article on Explicit Programming appearing in the March 2003 OnJava Magazine</short_desc>
      <description>Contrasted the concepts of Design Markers and Explicit Programming in an article published in the March 2003 issue of O'Reilly's OnJava.com online magazines  It detailed how Design Markers can be used now to provide many of the benefits of Explicit Programming without relying on experimental tools.</description>
      <keywords list="Java, Design Markers, Explicit Programming, education"/>
    </project>
    <project start="12/2002" end="3/2003">
      <position title="Author" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Gamelan.com" location="Darien, CT" www="http://www.gamelan.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Rosemarie Graham" title="Editor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Wrote article on Design Markers appearing in the March 2003 Gamelan Magazine</short_desc>
      <description>Conceived the concept of Design Markers and wrote an article presenting the idea. It was published in the March 2003 issue of both the Gamelan.com and Developer.com online magazines.  It detailed how Marker Interfaces and JavaDoc can be combined to document Design Choices in the implementation source code.</description>
      <keywords list="Java, Design Markers, Explicit Programming, education"/>
    </project>
    <project start="8/2002" end="5/2003">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="ChoicePoint" location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.choicepoint.net/"/>
      <supervisor name="K. Deshpande" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="2"/>
      <short_desc>Developer of EJB based Business Credit Information Warehouse</short_desc>
      <description>Worked on multiple projects including developing XSLT transforms of XML bulk data into Oracle load scripts.  Was developer/mentor for a team developing the Business Identity Management middleware of a large Business Credit Information Warehouse that used EJB CMP 2.0 technology with Oracle.  Documented biometric information system using Struts. Integrated LDAP servers with Borland J2EE server developing custom JNDI and JAAS components.</description>
      <keywords list="Java, J2EE, EJB CMP 2.0, XML, XSLT, XSchema, JUnit, JBuilder,  BES, Win2000, Solaris, Oracle, JAAS, Design Patterns, UML, QA/QC, JNDI, LDAP, Struts, education, SQL, RUP, Rose, Unix, BPA"/>
    </project>
    <project start="4/2002" end="8/2002">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="PolyGlot, Inc." location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.polyglotinc.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Robert Wallace" title="Owner"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed a set of XML utilities for publishing resumes/job requirements</short_desc>
      <description>Ported GanntMagic, a set of Java/XML utilities for publishing resumes and job requirements in a number of formats including GANNT chart graphics, from standalone Java application to SVG/XML/XSLT based middleware integrated with an interactive web site using multi-threaded J2EE technologies.  An ontology was created to organize buzzwords enabling better search and summary results.</description>
      <keywords list="SVG, XML, DTD, XSLT, XSchema, XERCES, XALAN, Java, J2EE, JRun, MySQL, JDBC, JSP, JAXP, XHTML, HTML, ontology, Protege-2000, Linux, Win2000, Apache, Batik, SQL, Javascript, UML, architect, Unix"/>
    </project>
    <project start="11/2001" end="6/2002">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Grassroots Girls" location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.grassrootsgirls.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Renee Izadi" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="1"/>
      <short_desc>Automated web site production via custom Java/XML/XSLT utilites</short_desc>
      <description>Site architect and developer of a set of Java/XML/XSLT utilities for automating the generation of dynamic pages on their web site. Also, taught in-house classes on XML/XSLT. Was main liaison between business partners and web graphics designer.  Also developed server side scripts in PHP to support forms and order processing.</description>
      <keywords list="XML, XSLT, DTD, XSchema, XHTML, HTML, CSS, Java, J2EE, education, workflow, XALAN, XERCES, JAXP, JRun, Apache, ANT, Linux, PHP, Win2000, Internet, e-commerce, UML, architect, Unix, BPA"/>
    </project>
    <project start="2/2001" end="10/2001">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="MediaBin" location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.mediabin.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Bill Coleman" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Lead Java Developer porting client/server API from C++ to Java</short_desc>
      <description>Ported from C++ to Java the implementation of the client-side API of the MediaBin Image and Asset Mgmnt System.  This multi-threaded Java middleware managed the C++ server via proprietary client/server protocols using BER encoding and ASN style protocol layers on top of TCP/IP.  I also developed an extensive (over 500 tests) unit test suite using the open std JUnit test framework and JBuilder IDE.</description>
      <keywords list="Java, C++, JUnit, JBuilder, GDPro, Win2000, image mgmnt, BER-ASN-TCP/IP protocols, Design Patterns, UML, QA/QC"/>
    </project>
    <project start="10/2000" end="2/2001">
      <position title="Author" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="JavaPro Magazine" location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.polyglotinc.com/reflection.html"/>
      <supervisor name="Kay Keppler" title="Editor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Wrote article on design patterns appearing in the March 2001 JavaPro Magazine</short_desc>
      <description>Wrote an article on the Visitor design pattern which was published in the March 2001 issue of JavaPro Magazine.  It detailed how Java's reflection API can be used to greatly simplify the implementation of the GoF Visitor pattern.</description>
      <keywords list="Java, Visitor Pattern, Reflection, education"/>
    </project>
    <project start="3/2000" end="1/2001">
      <position title="Tech Asst to Chairman" type="Employee"/>
      <client name="Matrix.net" location="Austin, TX" www="http://www.matrix.net/"/>
      <supervisor name="Don Fussell" title="Chief Science Officer"/>
      <staff headcount="2"/>
      <short_desc>Lead Portal and J2EE Developer</short_desc>
      <description>Managed, from software purchase negotiations thru development and developer training, the Portal portion of a product delivering network monitoring info via a web user interface. The project used the Epicentric portal framework and JRun JSP/servlet engine on top of a JDBC database and Apache web server.  Also, designed,  implemented and built automated testing of a servlet-based Configuration Server middleware for the Java and Perl components of the product.  Performed all development remotely via Internet telecommuting.</description>
      <keywords list="Portals, Java, Servlets, JSP, J2EE, JDBC, HTML, CSS, Perl, Solaris, Linux, TCP/IP, ICMP, XML, Epicentric, JRun, MySQL, Apache, architect, Win95, SQL, UML, Unix, BPA, QA/QC"/>
    </project>
    <project start="6/1999" end="3/2000">
      <position title="Lead Developer" type="Employee"/>
      <client name="Nuforia" location="Houston, TX" www="http://www.redsky.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Michael Wollin" title="Dir., Engineering"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Lead developer for the Atlanta office</short_desc>
      <description>Hired as lead developer for the Atlanta office of an internet consulting start-up.  Participated in OO Analysis JAD of a CRM system for private credit card client, Enterprise Portal development using Epicentric middleware and custom servlets/JSPs, and taught Java and J2EE technology classes to both in-house and client developers.  Specialized in multi-tier distributed/internet/intranet systems.</description>
      <keywords list="e-commerce, Portals, education. CRM, Java, Servlets, JSP, J2EE, EJB, HTML, CSS, WinNT, Linux, TCP/IP,  network admin, firewalls, XML, Epicentric, WebLogic, Apache, SQL, UML, Unix, BPA"/>
    </project>
    <project start="4/1999" end="6/1999">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="QWIZ, Inc." location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.qwiztek.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Tina Babb" title="Project Lead"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Member of expert panels developing online tests for Java 2 and HTML 4.0</short_desc>
      <description>Was one of 3 experts on two separate panels that researched and produced questions and answers for online testing of Java 2 and HTML 4 skills.</description>
      <keywords list="Java, HTML, CSS, education"/>
    </project>
    <project start="3/1998" end="4/1999">
      <position title="Chief Technical Officer" type="Employee"/>
      <client name="fabric.com" location="Marietta, GA" www="http://www.fabric.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Stephen Friedman" title="President"/>
      <staff headcount="22"/>
      <short_desc>CTO for an e-commerce / online-auction / industry-portal startup</short_desc>
      <description>Took over as a hands-on CTO of a small startup that had lost its entire technical staff midway through its seed funding cycle.  Was in charge of all technical aspects of the company, focused on marrying internet commerce with the textile and apparel industries.  Reporting to the President, I managed all software development, both in-house, outsourced and licensed, as well as technical architecture development and support.  Web sites included retail stores for clients like Hancock Fabrics, Java-based real-time auctions for clients like Walt Disney Company, and the portal sites www.fabric.com and www.apparelex.com.  Developed infrastructure to collect data from online activities and data mine it to support email and fax based promotions. Also developed enterprise data integration and workflow middleware to automate internal operations wherever possible.  Directed 5 staff members and 17 contractors from 7 different vendors.</description>
      <keywords list="management, e-commerce, BPA/BPR, workflow, data modeling, data mining, database admin, Filemaker, Access, Oracle, Java, Javascript, Perl, HTML, Cold Fusion, network admin, WinNT, Win95, Linux, architect, SQL, UML, Unix"/>
    </project>
    <project start="11/1997" end="1/1998">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="PolyGrafX" location="Chattanooga, TN" www="http://www.polygrafxstudios.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Scott Wallace" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed a set of Java/XML utilities for publishing resumes</short_desc>
      <description>Developed GanntMagic, a set of Java/XML utilities for publishing resumes and job requirements in a number of formats including graphical GANNT charts. Also, taught in-house classes on XML.</description>
      <keywords list="XML, DTD, Java, education, graphics, Solaris, Win95, Unix"/>
    </project>
    <project start="7/1997" end="2/1998">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract-W2"/>
      <client name="Javasoft (Sun)" location="Cupertino, CA" www="http://www.javasoft.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Frank Dibbell" title="SQE Manager"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>In charge of developing Java applets for HotJava Browser test suite</short_desc>
      <description>Was in charge of developing a set of Java applets to test a broad range of Java APIs available in the HotJava Browser environment, especially security limits.  APIs included Java Beans, GUI, networking, communications, system calls, etc. Also developed a multi-threaded HTTP server written in Java with special server side include processing to support browser stress testing.</description>
      <keywords list="Java, HTML, HTTP, Solaris, Win95, QA/QC, JDK, Visual Cafe, JBuilder, JavaStudio, Unix"/>
    </project>
    <project start="9/1996" end="3/1998">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="MIDS" location="Austin, TX" www="http://www.internetweather.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="John Quarterman" title="President"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>developed Java applets for Internet Weather Map viewing</short_desc>
      <description>Developed a data visualization applet in Java that enables Web users to see Internet data storms.  Also, wrote Java applications to poll web sites and collect performance statistics. MIDS collects a database of statistics about data flow over the entire Internet. Performed all development remotely via Internet telecommuting.</description>
      <keywords list="Java, HTML, HTTP, JDK, Visual Cafe, Solaris, Win95, Macintosh, Unix"/>
    </project>
    <project start="6/1996" end="5/1997">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract-W2"/>
      <client name="Coca-Cola" location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.coke.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Tamara Wright" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Support and extend a MacApp-based client/server data warehouse</short_desc>
      <description>Helped support &amp; extend Coke's custom Macintosh client software for a client/server data warehouse system. The databases were implemented with Oracle and Teradata servers. The Macintosh software was implemented with MacApp 3.1 using CodeWarrior and C++.  Helped develop proof of concept for porting Mac and PC versions of software to a single 3-tier implementation in Java.</description>
      <keywords list="Java, C++, MacApp, CodeWarrior, SQL, client/server, data warehouse, Booch"/>
    </project>
    <project start="3/1996" end="6/1996">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="IRI Logistics" location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.infores.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Vittal Devarajan" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Helped port MRP/DRP system from PL/SQL to C/Oracle/Informix</short_desc>
      <description>Helped to port and enhance the Logistics Partner DRP product from Oracle PL/SQL to C, Oracle Pro*C, &amp; Informix ESQL-C on HPUX and AIX platforms. Developed preprocessor language to enable common source files to generate both Pro*C and ESQL-C embedded SQL. Was in charge of integration of all backend server code produced by 6 developers.</description>
      <keywords list="HPUX, AIX, C, Oracle Pro*C, Informix ESQL-C, MRP/DRP, compilers, Unix, SQL"/>
    </project>
    <project start="5/1995" end="2/1996">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="BellSouth Wireless" location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.cellemetry.com/pr1999/Nov_18_1999.html"/>
      <supervisor name="Steve Cleary" title="Senior Manager"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Architect of server software for BellSouth's Cellemetry service</short_desc>
      <description>Designed software architecture &amp; implemented multi-threaded / multi-process message routing kernal of the Cellemetry system for performing telemetry transparently over existing cellular phone systems. This effort included development of fault-tolerant middleware and inter-system protocols. The system was written in C/C++ using the DGM&amp;S Omni toolkit and IS41/SS7 network interface. Also programmed HP IS41 protocol analyser in HP Pascal.</description>
      <keywords list="C, C++, UnixWare, message oriented middleware, telecom systems, IS41,SS7, PERL, DGM&amp;S, Pascal, Booch, Unix"/>
    </project>
    <project start="4/1994" end="4/1995">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract-W2"/>
      <client name="BellSouth Cellular" location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.bellsouth.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Gary Schwaiger" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="2"/>
      <short_desc>Created Middleware for Real-time Cellular Phone Billing System</short_desc>
      <description>Architect of middleware layer as well as portions of the application layer for a multi-threaded real-time billing network for cellular phone services. The system was written in C++ using Sybase, DCE, &amp; SNMP on AIX and HPUX servers. Developed real-time process control, communications, and monitoring using custom X windows graphics displays and SNMP interface to NetView &amp; SM/6000. Taught in-house classes on Object Oriented development and C++.</description>
      <keywords list="C++, AIX, HPUX, Sybase, DCE, SNMP, NetView, SM/6000, distributed systems, X Windows, SQL, education, Booch, Unix, BPA"/>
    </project>
    <project start="4/1994" end="6/1994">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Digital Enterprises" location="Atlanta, GA" www=""/>
      <supervisor name="Keith Tener" title="President"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed system to monitor/log RAID disk status notifying alerts via digital pagers</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="Win31, MS-DOS, C/C++, telecommunications, protocol design, sole-developer, embedded, Booch"/>
    </project>
    <project start="6/1993" end="11/1994">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract-W2"/>
      <client name="Georgia Power" location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.southerncompany.com/gapower/"/>
      <supervisor name="The Computer Merchant" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed reporting apps for Board of Directors using ObjectPAL (Paradox for Windows)</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="ObjectVision, ObjectPAL, Paradox for Windows, Crystal Reports, Win31, Booch, BPA"/>
    </project>
    <project start="2/1993" end="3/1994">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract-W2"/>
      <client name="Coca-Cola" location="Atlanta, GA" www="http://www.coke.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Karen Gratton" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed Macintosh GUIs for Coke's marketing data warehouse</short_desc>
      <description>Helped develop two marketing promotions tracking systems for Coke where Macintosh and MS Windows custom applications were written to provide a uniform GUI front end to SQL databases. The databases were implemented with Oracle via central servers. The PC clients used Oracle PRO*C embedded SQL pre-compiler. The Macintosh programs were implemented with MacApp 3.0 using MPW and C++.</description>
      <keywords list="C++, MPW, MacApp, Oracle, Pro*C, SQL, client/server, Win31, Booch"/>
    </project>
    <project start="1/1993" end="2/1993">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Raytheon" location="Marlborough, MA" www="http://www.raytheon.com/c3i/c3iproducts/c3iatc/atcin.htm"/>
      <supervisor name="Martin Greenstein" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Helped develop a rapid-prototype of an air-traffic control system</short_desc>
      <description>Helped develop a rapid-prototype of an air-traffic control system. The system was used to demonstrate the capability of developing an ATC system built with open systems components (Unix, X). Dataviews middleware was chosen as the rapid prototyping tool. Interfaced with actual ATC radar data from Frankfurt, Germany (DERD) and drove custom Sony 2K by 2K pixel color displays.</description>
      <keywords list="C, DGUX, SunOS, Unix, X, Motif, DataViews, real-time, twm, mwm, graphics, embedded"/>
    </project>
    <project start="11/1992" end="2/1993">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="BenefitWare" location="Stone Mtn, GA" www=""/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed insurance direct reimbursement program using ObjectVision</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="ObjectVision, Win31"/>
    </project>
    <project start="10/1992" end="12/1993">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract-W2"/>
      <client name="Federal Express" location="Memphis, TN" www="http://www.fedex.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="GE Consulting" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Wrote a white paper on X GUI interoperability &amp; style guidelines</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="X Windows, Motif, XLOOK, GUI, Unix"/>
    </project>
    <project start="1/1992" end="10/1992">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="V.I. Corporation" location="Northampton, MA" www="http://www.dvcorp.com/AboutUs.Htm"/>
      <supervisor name="Earl Billingsley" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Helped develop interactive GUI editors for DataViews customers</short_desc>
      <description>Helped develop interactive GUI editors for Commonwealth Edison, Hitachi, and Talarian using DataViews middleware, Unix, C, and X windows/Motif. The user could easily produce screens with real-time input &amp; output elements that were linked via shared memory to user application programs. These editors were built with the DataViews GUI development package from V.I. Corporation as well as Xt &amp; Motif.  Also, developed a real-time digital radio GUI for ITT using DataViews rapid-prototyping tools on top of Open Look.</description>
      <keywords list="C, C++, Unix, X, XDesigner, Motif, DataViews, real-time, SunOS, HPUX, DGUX"/>
    </project>
    <project start="11/1991" end="12/1991">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Lockheed Missles &amp; Space" location="Sunnyvale, CA" www="http://lmms.external.lmco.com/defsys/thaad.html"/>
      <supervisor name="VI Corp" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Helped test &amp; debug ERIS launch control console software</short_desc>
      <description>As a DataViews middleware consultant, I performed an informal software audit of the launch control console software for the ERIS program focusing on a particular set of problems.  I produced a report of the general state of the software as well as recommended changes.</description>
      <keywords list="DataViews, Fortran, Modula, GUI, QA/QC, VAX VMS"/>
    </project>
    <project start="7/1991" end="11/1991">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Chevron Oil" location="Richmond, CA" www="http://www.chevrontexaco.com/news/archive/chevron%5Fpress/2001/2001%2D09%2D05.asp"/>
      <supervisor name="Rick Scheuerman" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="1"/>
      <short_desc>Overhauled oil refinery pilot plant realtime GUI monitoring systems</short_desc>
      <description>Overhauled an oil refinery pilot plant monitoring system using DataViews middleware, Ingres, Vax VMS, C, and FORTRAN. This real-time system included several processes, distributed over DecNet, which communicated via message and file passing. Object-Oriented techniques were used in the redesign and implementation.  System made extensive use of the DataViews GUI development package from V.I. Corporation.</description>
      <keywords list="VAX, VMS, C, FORTRAN, DecWindows, DataViews, Ingres, DecNet, real-time, graphics, client/server, embedded"/>
    </project>
    <project start="11/1989" end="5/1991">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Orbital Engine Co." location="Perth, West Australia" www="http://www.orbeng.com.au/orbital/engineeringServices/testingValidation.htm"/>
      <supervisor name="Mark Norman" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="3"/>
      <short_desc>Developed realtime Unix/X GUI for automobile engine testing systems</short_desc>
      <description>Developed an automobile engine test &amp; measurement system in DGUX, C, Progress 4GL, and X windows based on an existing system in DG/AOS FORTRAN. I developed a multi-threaded real-time middleware system which managed communications and synchronization via System V IPC. Object-Oriented development techniques were used in the design and implementation. System used HP75000 and HP3852 GPIB bus mainframes, IDEC Izumi PLCs, and Ono Sokki flow meters. Taught in house classes on Object Oriented development.</description>
      <keywords list="AOS, DGUX, FORTRAN, C, C++, Progress 4GL, X, Xlib, Motif, graphics, QA/QC, MS-DOS, real-time, relational database, education, architect, embedded, Unix"/>
    </project>
    <project start="7/1989" end="10/1989">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Pillar Corporation" location="Foster City, CA" www=""/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed MacApp objects to read/write Lotus &amp; DBase files</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="MacApp, OOP, DBASE, Object Pascal, Macintosh"/>
    </project>
    <project start="4/1989" end="9/1989">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Operations Control Systems" location="Palo Alto, CA" www="http://www.tidalsoft.com/news/press_releases/download/TIDAL_PR.pdf"/>
      <supervisor name="Derek Evans" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed OCS/Make, a UNIX-like make facility for HP3000 systems</short_desc>
      <description>Developed an object-oriented UNIX-like make facility for HP3000 systems to be marketed as a stand-alone product OCS/Make as well  as being integrated into the OCS/Librarian product. Also produced maintenance &amp; upgrade changes to OCS/Librarian.</description>
      <keywords list="HP3000, MPE V, Image, View, Pascal/3000, Unix, architect"/>
    </project>
    <project start="1/1989" end="3/1989">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Stanley-Vidmar" location="Cincinnati, OH" www="http://www.stanleyvidmar.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Kit Fitzpatric" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Helped develop Apple's Flexible Manufacturing System (FMS)</short_desc>
      <description>Helped port and extend a real-time manufacturing controls system from an MS-DOS environment to the Macintosh. This version of the system was specifically for use in Apple Computer's Flexible Manufacturing System (FMS) in Fremont, California. The system controlled 1500 rotary storage locations along with assorted robot extractor/inserters and conveyors. It also updated part inventory and daily production schedule databases. The control system communicated with controllers from other vendors over AppleTalk network links.</description>
      <keywords list="Macintosh, MPW, C, DB-Vista databases, MS-DOS,  IBM PC/AT, real-time, manufacturing, protocol design, communications, AppleTalk, embedded"/>
    </project>
    <project start="11/1988" end="1/1989">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="MasterPlan, Inc." location="Foster City, CA" www=""/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Taught in-house classes on MacApp and OO development</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="MacApp, OOP, Object Pascal, Macintosh, education"/>
    </project>
    <project start="4/1988" end="6/1988">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Ruocco &amp; Saucedo" location="San Jose, CA" www="http://www.justadvocates.com/firms/firm.cfm?ID=206"/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Wrote plan to implement new office LAN in a small law firm</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="Macintosh, LAN, network design, BPA"/>
    </project>
    <project start="3/1988" end="12/1988">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Cameo Systems" location="Santa Clara, CA" www="http://search.chemweek.com/%7Ecearchive/start_search/095/08/0193.html"/>
      <supervisor name="Fred Hyden" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="2"/>
      <short_desc>Macintosh team leader for CIM system for Genentech</short_desc>
      <description>Macintosh team leader on project to develop computer-integrated-manufacturing (CIM) system for Genentech. Designed and implemented workstation prototypes.  Macintoshes were connected to Tandem mainframe which handled central SQL database.</description>
      <keywords list="Macintosh, MPW, MacApp, Object Pascal, CIM, SQL, object oriented, 4th Dimension 4GL, protocol design, client/server"/>
    </project>
    <project start="1/1988" end="3/1988">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Schlage Electronics" location="Palo Alto, CA" www="http://www.schlagelock.com/brands/ebolt/"/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed electronic lock controller firmware</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="6800, device drivers, embedded, assembler"/>
    </project>
    <project start="7/1987" end="2/1988">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Verilink" location="San Jose, CA" www="http://www.verilink.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Starry Chan" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="3"/>
      <short_desc>Developed network management system for Verilink's T1 CSU/DSUs</short_desc>
      <description>Developed the multi-threaded software for a network management system for interfacing to Verilink's several types of T1 span monitoring equipment using D4/ESF protocols. The system allowed interactive access to individual nodes in the network as well as out-of-service testing (e.g. loopbacks). Background processing included alarm logging and performance data gathering. Wrote a complete OSI based transport system to implement secure communications between nodes over open phone lines with modems.</description>
      <keywords list="communications, OSI, T1 (D4/ESF), protocol design, real-time, IBM PC/AT, C, DB-Vista databases, MS-DOS, QA/QC, architect, embedded, 8052"/>
    </project>
    <project start="3/1987" end="6/1987">
      <position title="Product Manager" type="Employee"/>
      <client name="BAM" location="Sydney, Australia" www=""/>
      <supervisor name="Mike Bolan" title="President"/>
      <staff headcount="4"/>
      <short_desc>Product Manager for Enigma time management software for Macintosh</short_desc>
      <description>As product manager for this Macintosh time management program, I organized the development team consisting of people in Silicon Valley and Sydney, Australia.  The main competition for this product was Apple MacProject.</description>
      <keywords list="Macintosh, marketing, management, BPA"/>
    </project>
    <project start="11/1986" end="4/1987">
      <position title="Network Transport System Manager" type="Employee"/>
      <client name="Australian Associated Press" location="Sydney, Australia" www="http://aap.com.au/"/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="2"/>
      <short_desc>NTS Manager for national satellite communications network</short_desc>
      <description>Performed a system design review of AAP's national satellite communications network.  This involved analysis of the protocols of the various communication layers as well as software design.  The system is VAX based written in C involving satellite, microwave, and phone line segments for interactive distribution of financial and wire-service data.</description>
      <keywords list="communications, VAX, VMS, C, Ethernet, Decnet, protocols, design, management, embedded"/>
    </project>
    <project start="10/1986" end="10/1986">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Hoge, Fenton, Jones, &amp; Appel" location="San Jose, CA" www="http://www.hogefenton.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Helped develop client database system for law firm</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="DBASE, MS-DOS"/>
    </project>
    <project start="3/1986" end="9/1986">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="FMC" location="San Jose, CA" www="http://www.prnewswire.com/cgi-bin/stories.pl?ACCT=105&amp;STORY=/www/story/12-16-1998/0000826084"/>
      <supervisor name="John Tope" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed military vehicle simulations for prototype hardened-LAN</short_desc>
      <description>Developed military vehicle simulations to demonstrate a distributed electronic control system implemented on a custom hardened local area network.  Ten IBM AT computers where used to simulate various subsystems of trucks, tanks, APC, etc. and communicated over fiber-optic based network using distributed database techniques. Integrated modules produced by 2 other subcontractors.</description>
      <keywords list="IBM PC/AT,  Pascal,  LANs,  simulation,  military systems, distributed database"/>
    </project>
    <project start="7/1985" end="9/1986">
      <position title="Lecturer" type="Employee"/>
      <client name="Northeastern University" location="Sunnyvale, CA" www="http://www.northeastern.edu/"/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Faculty member, Pascal &amp; Prolog Instructor, Bay Area Regional Technology Center</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="Pascal, Prolog, education"/>
    </project>
    <project start="3/1985" end="2/1986">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Hewlett Packard" location="Cupertino, CA" www="http://www.hp.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Jean Danver" title="Manager"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed QA test suites for HP Pascal &amp; Modcal compilers</short_desc>
      <description>Developed test suite of spec compliance and regression tests for Pascal and Modcal compilers for HP3000,  HP9920, and HP Spectrum computers on MPE, HPUX, and HPE operating systems. Developed tools to automate QA/QC process. Also performed some compiler maintenance.</description>
      <keywords list="QA/QC, HP-3000, HP-9920, HP-Spectrum, Pascal, Modcal, C, HPE, MPE, HPUX,  Unix, HP Image database, compilers"/>
    </project>
    <project start="1/1985" end="2/1986">
      <position title="Entrant/Developer" type="Volunteer"/>
      <client name="Othello Championship" location="Northridge, CA" www="http://perso.wanadoo.fr/brunodlb/ot_story.htm"/>
      <supervisor name="Marc Furon" title="Tournament Director"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed entry in North Amer. Computer Othello Championship Tournament</short_desc>
      <description>Wrote POP, two programs to play the Othello game, one for the IBM PC, and the other for the Macintosh. The IBM PC version was entered into the North American Computer Othello Championship Tournament (Feb 15-16, 1986). I personally had won tournaments where I played against computer programs and human opponents. POP successfully implemented my playing strategy.</description>
      <keywords list="Macintosh, IBM PC/AT, simulation, real-time, graphics, Pascal, sole-developer"/>
    </project>
    <project start="5/1984" end="9/1984">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Formaster" location="Santa Clara, CA" www="http://www.thebrennergroup.com/press4.shtml"/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed disk copy protection software for Macintosh</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="Macintosh, device drivers, Pascal, embedded, assembler, 68000"/>
    </project>
    <project start="3/1984" end="2/1985">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Applicon, Inc" location="Santa Clara, CA" www="http://www.deskeng.com/articles/99/Aug/bravo/index.htm"/>
      <supervisor name="David Ross" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Upgraded Applicon's VLSI CAD/CAM system software</short_desc>
      <description>Prototyped, in VAX C, a system to extract electrical circuit schematics from raw VLSI fabrication data. Also performed maintenance and upgrade programming for a multi-threaded VLSI CAD/CAM system based on PDP-11 &amp; custom hardware. Development was on VAX VMS.  Produced a new release in 8 weeks (no releases having been made in 2-l/2 years). </description>
      <keywords list="VLSI CAD/CAM,  PDP-11,  VAX,  RSX-llM, VMS, C, computational geometry, design maintenance, FORTRAN, Macro-11, FLECS, Pascal, compilers, device drivers, embedded, assembler"/>
    </project>
    <project start="2/1983" end="4/1983">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Bullwinkles Pizza" location="Cupertino, CA" www="http://www.worldfranchising.com/profiles/BullWink.htm"/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed graphical customer pickup reminder system</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="Apple II, Forth, graphics, device drivers, embedded"/>
    </project>
    <project start="1/1983" end="2/1984">
      <position title="Chief Scientist/Product Manager" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Management Blueprint Software" location="Los Gatos, CA" www=""/>
      <supervisor name="Mike Lodge" title="Vice President"/>
      <staff headcount="4"/>
      <short_desc>Developed a general purpose symantic-network database system</short_desc>
      <description>Developed a general purpose symantic-network database system based on AI general knowledge database techniques to facilitate implementation of MBS's application packages for various professions. Integrated the system with subcontracted software modules and user applications. Managed 4 other developers.</description>
      <keywords list="IBM PC/XT, UCSD Pascal, artificial intelligence, management, database kernal, architect, BPA"/>
    </project>
    <project start="9/1982" end="11/1982">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Pizza Time Theatre" location="Sunnyvale, CA" www="http://www.showbizpizzapage.com/history.htm"/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Taught in-house classes on Apple Pascal</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="Apple II, Apple Pascal, education"/>
    </project>
    <project start="8/1982" end="11/1982">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="CGW &amp; Associates" location="Mtn View, CA" www=""/>
      <supervisor name="Carl White" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Taught Introduction to Ada seminars at LeBaron Hotel</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="ADA, education, marketing"/>
    </project>
    <project start="4/1982" end="6/1982">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="National Info Systems" location="Cupertino, CA" www="http://www.nis.com/aboutus.html"/>
      <supervisor name="Richard Carlson" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Wrote market evaluation of Pascal-Plus compiler</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="Pascal, marketing"/>
    </project>
    <project start="3/1982" end="1/1983">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Management Blueprint Software" location="Los Gatos, CA" www=""/>
      <supervisor name="Mike Lodge" title="Vice President"/>
      <staff headcount="2"/>
      <short_desc>Developed PolyForm, a general purpose forms processing system</short_desc>
      <description>Developed PolyForm, a general purpose forms processing system with a form definition language interpreter, to facilitate implementation of the MBS customizable application package Presidents War Plan. Managed 2 other developers.</description>
      <keywords list="Apple II, Apple III, IBM PC, TRS-80 II, Pascal, management, compilers, CAI, architect"/>
    </project>
    <project start="1/1982" end="3/1982">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="LeCroy, Inc." location="Palo Alto, CA" www="http://www.lecroy.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed laboratory equipment device drivers</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="8085, device drivers, embedded, assembler"/>
    </project>
    <project start="11/1981" end="1/1982">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Strobe, Inc." location="Mtn View, CA" www=""/>
      <supervisor name="Bob Sherwood" title="VP, Marketing"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed Pen Plotter device drivers for Apple II and CP/M</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="Basic, Z80, device drivers, Apple II, CP/M, embedded, assembler"/>
    </project>
    <project start="10/1981" end="9/1982">
      <position title="Author" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="ADC Associates" location="Palo Alto, CA" www=""/>
      <supervisor name="Arnie Roberts" title="Publisher"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed/Published VisiTran data translator for the Apple II</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="Apple II, Basic, VisiCalc, marketing, sole-developer"/>
    </project>
    <project start="6/1981" end="5/1982">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="OMEX" location="Santa Clara, CA" www=""/>
      <supervisor name="Rob Spade" title="Project Leader"/>
      <staff headcount="3"/>
      <short_desc>Team Leader for Posting on USA's largest title insurance system</short_desc>
      <description>Team Leader in charge of design and implementation of the Batch Posting portion of the nations's largest automated title insurance system. Taught in-house Pascal seminars for other project teams.  Designed high and low level database transaction languages and wrote a compiler for the HOL and an interpreter for the LOL which drove the ADABASE-M system.</description>
      <keywords list="Omsi Pascal, PDP-11/70, RSX-llM, management, design, ADABAS-M database, BPA"/>
    </project>
    <project start="4/1981" end="6/1981">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="DCM, Inc." location="San Leandro, CA" www="http://www.dcmindustries.com/history.htm"/>
      <supervisor name="" title=""/>
      <staff headcount="1"/>
      <short_desc>Developed multi-threaded controller for telephone cable test equipment</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="Z80, Pascal, CP/M, O/S kernals, real-time,  device drivers, embedded, assembler"/>
    </project>
    <project start="4/1981" end="9/1981">
      <position title="Author" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Quality Software" location="Reseda, CA" www="http://www.cyberroach.com/analog/an01/an1-038.htm"/>
      <supervisor name="Quality Software" title="Publisher"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed/Published "Meteoroids in Space" (sequel to Asteroids)</short_desc>
      <description>Wrote Meteoroids in Space, an upgrade/sequel to Asteroids in Space, an arcade game for the APPLE II. Was voted No. 5 in the All Time Favorite list of APPLE II programs in poll released by SOFTALK magazine.</description>
      <keywords list="APPLE II, 6502, simulation, real-time graphics, Pascal, software protection, marketing, sole-developer, device drivers, embedded, assembler, multi-threaded"/>
    </project>
    <project start="2/1981" end="4/1981">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="GenRad S.T.I." location="Milpitas, CA" www="http://www.genrad.com/products/default_products.htm"/>
      <supervisor name="Tony Taylor" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Ported FutureData systems from C to Z80 assembly language</short_desc>
      <description>Provided recommendations for choosing Z80 development system. Wrote a system for translating from any assembler mnemonics to another based on user specifications. Assisted engineers in checkout of target hardware. In charge of converting C programs running on PDP-11 to run on Z80 based machines.</description>
      <keywords list="Z80, Pascal, C, PDP-11, RSX-llM, embedded, assembler"/>
    </project>
    <project start="5/1980" end="5/1981">
      <position title="Author" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Byte Magazine" location="SF, CA" www="http://www.byte.com/"/>
      <supervisor name="Byte Magazine" title="Publisher"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Wrote article on computer animation appearing in the May 1981 Byte Magazine</short_desc>
      <description/>
      <keywords list="Apple Pascal, UCSD Pascal, Apple II, education"/>
    </project>
    <project start="4/1980" end="2/1981">
      <position title="Consultant" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Aydin Energy Division" location="Palo Alto, CA" www="http://www.epa.gov/oerrpage/superfund/sites/arcsites/c3ca/a0901399.htm"/>
      <supervisor name="Art Laursen" title="Supervisor"/>
      <staff headcount="10"/>
      <short_desc>Architect of realtime control systems for Lawrence Livermore Labs</short_desc>
      <description>In charge of software design and implementation for a $25 million subcontract to a Lawrence Livermore Labs fusion reactor experiment. The contract called for 24 10-megawatt power supply control systems and 4 maintenance consoles interfaced to the power supplies. Wrote an entire multi-threaded multi-tasking system in Z80 used as the kernel and interfaced an off-the-shelf Pascal compiler to the custom operating system. Managed l0 other programmers on the project.</description>
      <keywords list="Z80, Pascal, CP/M, O/S kernals, real-time, management, device drivers, architect, embedded, assembler"/>
    </project>
    <project start="1/1980" end="4/1980">
      <position title="Author" type="Contract"/>
      <client name="Quality Software" location="Reseda, CA" www="http://apple2history.org/history/appy/aha78.html"/>
      <supervisor name="Quality Software" title="Publisher"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Developed/Published "Asteroids in Space". Considered a classic by Softalk Magazine</short_desc>
      <description>Wrote Asteroids in Space, an arcade game for the APPLE II. Was voted No. 5 in the All Time Favorite list of APPLE II programs in poll released by SOFTALK magazine. Also added upgrades to version released as Meteoroids in Space.</description>
      <keywords list="APPLE II, 6502, simulation, real-time graphics, Pascal, software protection, marketing, sole-developer, embedded, device drivers, assembler, multi-threaded"/>
    </project>
    <project start="10/1979" end="3/1980">
      <position title="Software Development Manager" type="Employee"/>
      <client name="Personal Software (Visicorp)" location="Sunnyvale, CA" www="http://www.businessheroes.com/Pages/history/history2.htm"/>
      <supervisor name="Peter Jennings" title="Chairman"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Software Development Manager for publisher of VisiCalc</short_desc>
      <description>Managed several independent authors of microcomputer software.  Performed QA/QC and porting activities for entire product line. This was during the time that VisiCalc was introduced. Mitch Capor took this position when I left. He left 6 months later to start Lotus.</description>
      <keywords list="APPLE II, TRS-80, PET, management, QA/QC"/>
    </project>
    <project start="9/1978" end="9/1979">
      <position title="MAXBASIC Project Manager" type="Employee"/>
      <client name="National Info Systems" location="Cupertino, CA" www="http://www.nis.com/aboutus.html"/>
      <supervisor name="Arden Scott" title="President"/>
      <staff headcount="1"/>
      <short_desc>Project manager for MAXBASIC compiler product</short_desc>
      <description>Took over managing the MAXBASIC compiler project for DEC-10 and DEC-20 computers when it was two thirds complete with over 200 extant bug reports. Instituted a bug report/enhancement request system used by entire product line of company.</description>
      <keywords list="DEC-10/20, TOPS-l0/20, BASIC, Macro-l0/20, compilers, management, QA/QC, assembler"/>
    </project>
    <project start="9/1978" end="5/1984">
      <position title="President" type="Volunteer"/>
      <client name="Apple P.I.E." location="Sunnyvale, CA" www="http://www.pieinc.org/"/>
      <supervisor name="Mark Wozniak" title="Sponsor"/>
      <staff headcount="4"/>
      <short_desc>President of Apple II enthusiasts club (also taught formal classes)</short_desc>
      <description>Held various offices in Apple P.I.E. (Programming and Interfacing Enthusiasts) club including President, Vice President, and Secretary where I variously organized featured speakers, presided over meetings, and organized club software library.  Also, taught formal 10 week class on Apple Pascal. Meetings were held at the computer store owned by Steve Wozniak's brother Mark.</description>
      <keywords list="Apple II, education, management, Pascal, 6502, assembler"/>
    </project>
    <project start="3/1978" end="9/1978">
      <position title="Programmer/Analyst" type="Employee"/>
      <client name="Control Data Corp" location="Sunnyvale, CA" www="http://www.digitalcentury.com/encyclo/update/cdc.html"/>
      <supervisor name="Jen Bryant" title="Group Manager"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Member of Operating System Group for CDC Star supercomputer</short_desc>
      <description>Member of Operating System Group for CDC Star supercomputer.  Developed tools in FORTRAN-like language in which O/S was written. Learned structured development methodology and source code control systems.</description>
      <keywords list="FORTRAN, CDC NOS, CDC Star, supercomputers, operating systems, mainframe"/>
    </project>
    <project start="9/1974" end="1/1977">
      <position title="Programmer/Analyst" type="Contract-W2"/>
      <client name="Applications Group, FSU" location="Tallahassee, FL" www="http://gtcr.fsu.edu/"/>
      <supervisor name="Don McEwen" title="Manager"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Wrote applications for various Depts of the State of Florida</short_desc>
      <description>Designed/implemented applications for clients contracting with the Florida State University computing center in the following areas: Industrial Regression Model, Census Data Processing, Resource Use Projection, Pollution Monitoring Data Processing, Felony Caseload Data Processing, Student Evaluation Data Processing. Taught graphics seminars for FSU computing center.</description>
      <keywords list="CDC 6000, KRONOS, COMPASS, FORTRAN, COBOL, graphics, data processing, education, mainframe, assembler"/>
    </project>
    <project start="1/1974" end="12/1977">
      <position title="Student" type="Student"/>
      <client name="Florida State University" location="Tallahassee, FL" www="http://www.fsu.edu/"/>
      <supervisor name="Math/Computer Science" title="Major"/>
      <staff headcount="0"/>
      <short_desc>Math/Computer Science graduate of Florida State University</short_desc>
      <description>Design and implementation of the EXLAX language/compiler used in a numerical analysis class. Implementation of discrete event simulation of queue network.  Design/implementation of graphic 3-D maze game on PLATO system.  Completed every course offered in the computer science curriculum with a 3.6 GPA. Tutored computer science students for extra money.</description>
      <keywords list="APL, Basic, CDC 6000, KRONOS, COMPASS, Pascal, FORTRAN, TUTOR, PLATO, compilers, language design, simulation, LISP, SNOBOL, COBOL, education, graphics, mainframe, assembler"/>
    </project>
  </person>
</resumes>
